<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The angels oath, time is no longer The kingdoms of this world, are become the kingdoms of our Lord, and of his Christ, and he shall reign for ever and ever, Revel.10.6. and 11,15. A prophecy from Mr. Mason's people at Water-Stratford.</title>
            <author>Glover, Elizabeth, fl. 1694.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1694</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 62 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 24 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A75349</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3163CA</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R230971</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99896744</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99896744</idno>
            <idno type="VID">170770</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A75349)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 170770)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2433:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The angels oath, time is no longer The kingdoms of this world, are become the kingdoms of our Lord, and of his Christ, and he shall reign for ever and ever, Revel.10.6. and 11,15. A prophecy from Mr. Mason's people at Water-Stratford.</title>
                  <author>Glover, Elizabeth, fl. 1694.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[6], 40 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for the author,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Partly in verse.</note>
                  <note>Signature at end - Elizabeth Glover.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Bible --  Devotional literature --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Bible. --  N.T. --  Revelation --  Prophecies --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Angels --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>God --  Attributes --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>Aptara</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:170770:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>
               <hi>THE
<hi>Angels Oath,</hi>
               </hi>
Time is no longer.</p>
            <q>
               <p>The KINGDOMS of this
WORLD, are become
the KINGDOMS of our
Lord, and of his Chriſt,
and he ſhall Reign for
ever and ever,</p> 
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Revel.</hi> 10. 6.
and 11, 15.</bibl>
            </q>
            <p>A
PROPHECY
FROM
Mr. Maſon's People
AT
WATER-STRATFORD.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for the Author, 1694.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="testimony">
            <pb facs="tcp:170770:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:170770:2"/>
            <head>The Teſtimony of Valentine Evans.</head>
            <p>WO to <hi>London!</hi> Wo to <hi>England!</hi>
Thou art that Servant which hath
known thy Maſters Will, but hath not done
it; but now thou ſhalt be beaten with many
ſtripes. Oh! how Mercifully hath GOD
dealt with thee, by warning thee with
Judgments, and wooing thee with Mercies;
and thou haſt been favoured highly in this
reſpect; for the Revelation of Jeſus Chriſt
hath been given out to us, and the Meſſenger
of Chriſt's Kingdom hath been ſent to us,
and his way is prepared.</p>
            <p>I Witneſs, the <hi>Midnight-Cry</hi> was a
Meſſage from GOD. I declare, the <hi>Two
Witneſſes</hi> was a Meſsage from God. I de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare
likewiſe, in the Name of GOD, that
the gathering of us to this place, was the
Holy Will and Command of God. A few
days after we were gathered, I Witneſs,
the Perſon of the Bleſsed Son of GOD
<pb facs="tcp:170770:3"/>
appeared in this place to his Servant, but
you have ſcoffed and deſpiſed, and forged
Lies, and called theſe things Deluſions:
But what will you do now the Lord ſends
you word, by this fellow Servant, from the
Oath of Jeſus Chriſt, <hi>That there is Time
no longer.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Word to you <hi>Wiſe Virgins,</hi> you that
love the Lord Jeſus Chriſt in Sincerity;
you that have ſpoke or acted againſt theſe
things, you are guilty with the <hi>Fooliſh
Virgins,</hi> and have expoſed your ſelves to
Wrath; but, Bleſſed be God, you are not un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der
the Law, but under Grace; but you muſt
apply your ſelves to the Blood of Christ, and
repent for what you have ſaid, thought, or
done againſt theſe things, for GOD is a
great God, and you will Tremble for a time
for ſlighting theſe things, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 35. 3, 4.
<hi>ſtrengthen ye the weak hands, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort
the feeble knees:</hi> ſay to them that are
of a fearful heart, <hi>Be ſtrong, fear not:
Behold, your God will come with Ven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geance,
even God with a Recompence,
<pb facs="tcp:170770:3"/>
he will come and ſave you;</hi> but it muſt be
in his own way, and that is in this place,
which the Lord hath called Zion, where the
Lord hath taken poſſeſſion in his Kingdom,
Iſa. 25. 9. <hi>And it ſhall be ſaid in that
day, Lo, this is our God, we have waited
for him, and he will ſave us; this is the
Lord, we have waited for him, we will
be glad, and rejoyce in his ſalvation.</hi>
Verſ. 10. <hi>For in this Mountain ſhall the
hand of the Lord reſt:</hi> It is ſaid ſo this
day, in this Mountain, bleſſed be God:
<hi>Where the Body is, there the Eagles ſhall
be gathered together,</hi> Luk. 17. 37. And
now 'tis our Duty to look for the breaking
forth of theſe things viſibly, with an imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diate
expectation.</p>
            <p>The Grace of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt,
be with all you that love Him in ſincerity.
Amen.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="testimony">
            <pb facs="tcp:170770:4"/>
            <head>The Teſtimony of Thomas Harris.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>I</hi> Bear Witneſs to you, in the Name of
GOD, That this Servant that Writes
to you this <hi>Little Book,</hi> is one of the
<hi>Anointed Ones</hi> that ſtood by the GOD
of the whole Earth, <hi>Zech.</hi> 4. 14. and by
the Will and Appointment of <hi>GOD Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mighty,</hi>
this Servant did <hi>bear Record
to the Word of GOD, and to the Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimony
of Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> for Two Years
together, <hi>Rev.</hi> 1. 2. and now Bleſsed is
he that hath read, and they that have
heard the Words of the Prophecy of this
Book: and I declare, in the Name of GOD,
that this <hi>Book</hi> that comes to you, is the
<hi>open Book</hi> out of <hi>Chriſt</hi>'s Hand, <hi>Rev.</hi> 10.
2. and it is turned into <hi>Bitterneſs</hi> in the
Bowels of this Nation, <hi>Lamentations,
Mournings,</hi> and <hi>Woe:</hi> And now the
<hi>LORD</hi> comes like a <hi>Refiner</hi>'s Fire, and
like <hi>Fuller</hi>'s Soap: But now Bleſsed are
all they that put their Trust in <hi>CHRIST.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:170770:4"/>
            <epigraph>
               <bibl>Revelations 10. 6. and 11. 15.</bibl>
               <q>Time is no longer. The kingdoms of this world are
become the kingdoms of our Lord, and of his Christ,
and he ſhall reign for ever and ever.</q>
            </epigraph>
            <p>
               <hi>IT is the Will and Pleaſure of God, that his
dealings to this poor miſerable Nation, ſhould
be given an Account of, for a Warning and
Witneſs to all round about, that they take heed,
that they do not dally and triffle with the Word of
God, and the Teſtimony of Jeſus Chriſt; but Fear
and Tremble before a Crowned</hi> Solomon, <hi>and give
Glory to him, for the hour of his Judgment is come.
Worſhip that God that hath made</hi> the new Heavens
and the new Earth. Thou ſhalt break them with a rod
of iron, thou ſhalt daſh them in pieces like a Potters
veſſel. Be wiſe now therefore, O ye kings: be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructed
ye judges of the earth. Serve the Lord
with fear, and rejoice with trembling. Kiſs the ſon,
leſt he be angry, and ye periſh from the way, when
his wrath is kindled but a little: bleſſed are all they
that put their truſt in him, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 2. 9, 10, 11, 12.
Now go, write it before them in a table, and note it
in a book, that it may be for the time to come for ever
and ever: That this is a rebellious people, lying chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren,
that will not hear the law of the Lord: Which
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:170770:5"/>
ſay to the ſeers, See not; and to the prophets, Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſy
not unto us right things, ſpeak unto us ſmooth
things, propheſy deceits: Get you out of the way, turn
aſide out of the path, cauſe the holy one of Iſrael to ceaſe
from before us, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 30. 8, 9, 10, 11.</p>
            <p>Sad and woful Accounts to be given up, what
entertainment the Word of God, and the Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony
of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt met with, that was
firſt given forth in <hi>England;</hi> we witneſs, the Trum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pet
was ſounded ſeveral Years of the Coming and
Kingdom of our Lord, but they all ſlumbered and
ſlept; but they was told again and again, how
often that Word was commanded in the Scripture
<hi>Watch,</hi> and that the day was come, God com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded
every one to it.</p>
            <p>The Lord threatens to cut them down; for he
had looked for Fruit Year after Year, but found
none; loth was he to ſtrike, tryes them one Year
more, but ſwares, <hi>Time ſhall be no longer;</hi> but whilſt
the Miſtery of God was finiſhed, the Lord was then
proclaimed; <hi>He's brought to the ancient of days:
And there was given him a Kingdom, and Glory, that
all Nations, People, and Languages, ſhould ſerve him,</hi>
Dan. 7. 13, 14.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The many Crowns was now ſet upon his head,</hi> Rev.
19. 12. He was proclaimed to the ends of the
Earth. <hi>Zions</hi> God now reigns. The Earth ſaw
and trembled, the Heavens were all on Flames of
Fire, whilſt dreadful Thundrings and Lightnings
proclaim our King; but here is none regard.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:170770:5"/>
The Trumpets blew in the Ears of the dead; <hi>it
was declared,</hi> That Christ was on his great white
Throne; <hi>he finds all old, but makes all new.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Lord calls, bring in thoſe poor Worms, let
them bear witneſs in that day: <hi>The deaf heard the
words of the Book, and the Eyes of the blind were
opened.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Lord plants the Heavens, lays the Founda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
of the Earth, calls <hi>Zion,</hi> brings in the ends of
the Earth. The Beaſt is given to the burning flame,
he lays hold on the Dragon, (that old Serpent)
and binds him for 1000 Years. Thus things went
on, until the glorious Miſtery of God was finiſhed;
<hi>and the voice came from the Throne, out of the Temple
of heaven, ſaying, It is done,</hi> Rev. 16. 17.</p>
            <p>Often then it was declared, in the Name of
God, <hi>It is done,</hi> It is fulfilled, but they would not
believe: Then was <hi>Philadelphia</hi> called in to bare
witneſs what ſhe had ſeen done; ſhe witneſſed, that
the Heavens were planted, and the Foundations of
the Earth laid; for ſhe <hi>ſaw the new Heavens and
the new Earth;</hi> ſhe witneſſeth the New Covenant
for <hi>Zion,</hi> for ſhe <hi>ſaw the new Jeruſalem coming down
from God out of heaven, prepared as a bride adorned
for her husband.</hi> She atteſts, in the Name of God,
the hearing of that mighty Voice, <hi>The tabernacle
of God is with men.</hi> She muſt bear witneſs to the
Words of the Prophecy of the Book; and ſay as
God ſaith, <hi>There is no more ſorrow, death, nor pain,
for the former things are paſt. He hath ſate on his
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:170770:6"/>
throne, and made all new. And he ſaid unto me, Write,
for theſe words are true and faithful. And he ſaid
unto me, It is done.</hi> And this day is this Scripture
fulfilled in your Ears. <hi>And he hath given the waters
of life,</hi> and hath repleniſhed every ſorrowful Soul
that hath waited for him; they have <hi>Overcome,</hi>
and are on the Sea of Glaſs, with the Harps of <hi>God,</hi>
and they ſing the Song of <hi>Moſes,</hi> and the Lamb.
<hi>But the fearful, and unbelieving, and the abominable,
and the murderers, and whoremongers, and ſorcerers,
and idolaters, and all liars, have their part in the lake
that burneth with fire and brimſtone: which is the
ſecond death,</hi> Rev. 21. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.</p>
            <p>The Lord commands the Witneſs to go on; ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
comes and ſays, <hi>I ſaw an angel aſcending from
the eaſt, having the ſeals of the living God: And he
ſealed the ſervants of our God on their forehead,</hi> Rev.
7. 2, 3. Another Witneſs was brought, that he
hath <hi>meaſured the temple, and the altar, and them
that worſhip therein. But the outward court is given
unto the Gentiles<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> Rev. 11. 1, 2. <hi>He hath opened
his Seals, ſounded his Trumpets, poured out his Vials,
and bleſſed all his Churches.</hi> Thus the Witneſs
went on from day to day, until all Accounts was ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken,
and given in: <hi>Philadelphia</hi> ſometimes trem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bling
and quaking before the Majeſty of Heaven,
often acknowledging what an awful ſolemn thing
it was, to bear witneſs to the Word of God, and Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimony
of Jeſus Chriſt; other times aſtoniſhed and
amazed, to think, that Miſtery the Angels deſire to
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:170770:6"/>
pry into, ſhould ever be broken up among a few
poor Worms, The Lord declares, <hi>That he hath fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed
the heavens, and the Earth, and all the hoſts
thereof;</hi> as in the firſt Creation, <hi>All was done by his
Word;</hi> ſo now it is again, <hi>not by Might, nor by Power,
but by my ſpirit, ſaith the Lord of hoſts,</hi> Zech. 4. 6.</p>
            <p>And the Witneſs of the two anointed ones, was
the Witneſs of God himſelf: Now, who durſt have
denied the ſound of the ſeventh Angel, when God
had called in a Witneſs, that theſe Miſteries were
finiſhed, or that this was the Angel that was to be
ſent, to ſhew the things that muſt be done in a
ſhort time. When Scripture Witneſs was brought
in, that all theſe things are done, it was a very im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>probable
thing, that one, whoſe Unction from the
Holy One, for the Work of the Miniſtry, had been
ſealed for ſo many Years, with the Converſion
of ſo many Souls, ſhould at laſt deceive the
World, and delude poor Souls; but as for thoſe
poor Creatures that bear witneſs to theſe things,
they were not ſuſpected of that, being looked upon
as not capable to delude or deceive others; but
that they were deluded themſelves. It is poſſible,
had it been things of another nature, you might
have brought them off, by telling them, that their
bodily Eyes had deceived them, and all their Senſes
were deluded: But if you come to deal with them
about the Word of God, and Teſtimony of Jeſus,
you might as well pull down the Sun, and darken
the World, as ever prevail againſt it; for it is the
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:170770:7"/>
Teſtimony of that God which is infallible, there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
infinitely impoſſible that ever any thing that
is offered againſt it ſhould ſtand; it will be the
utter undoing of all them that ſhall oppoſe it: for
tho' theſe be never ſuch poor weak contemptable
Creatures, yet what they witneſs to is the Word
of God, and Teſtimony of Jeſus, and there is no
more to be ſaid. Evidence having been given,
<hi>That the miſtery of God is finiſhed; the mighty Angel
he comes down with a rainbow on his head, and a little
book open in his hand, and ſwares by him that lives
for ever and ever, Time is no longer.</hi> Come
away <hi>Philadelphia,</hi> and own his Kingly Dignity
and Honour; they had not been long dancing be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
the Ark, ere the Lord appeared to his Servant,
this he owns before many Witneſſes, warns them
once more to get Oyl, others to go home, and
trim their Lamps, they have no time to ſpare, they
ſhould have <hi>Watched,</hi> that God that hath appeared
in this place, will quickly appear to you all; but
what do theſe Wretches do, but go and make
all the haſt and ſpeed they can, to turn theſe things
into fooliſh ridiculous Stories, to be cry'd up and
down the Streets; and ſo far are they from any
fear or concern upon them, at ſuch a wonderful
time as this is, that they make merry, and ſport
themſelves at the Word of God, and Revelation of
Jeſus. It would make a Chriſtian's Heart tremble,
to think what a God-daring Generation the Earth
groans under. And now the Lord comes, like a
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:170770:7"/>
Lyon, rends and tears the very cauls of their hearts;
they would take no Warning, till they were daſhed
in pieces; but all the Wit and Art they have muſt
be laid together, to make the Word of God, and
Revelation of Jeſus, the Scorn and Deriſion of the
whole Nation, without any ſtop being put to theſe
things, there was none to do it. The Lord ſought
but for a Man to ſtand in the gap to make up the
hedge, that he ſhould not deſtroy the Land, but he
finds none, good and bad all give in their Verdicts,
that the Word of God, and Teſtimony of Jeſus
Chriſt, was a Deluſion; and ſo here is an end of all
theſe things, until God calls for another Account.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>But we do atteſt, in the Name of the Eternal
God, That the ſounding of the quick and ſudden
Coming of our Lord and Saviour, was the ſound
of the ſeventh Angel, and God hath given infallible
Proof and Witneſs, for the Miſtery of God is finiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed,
as he declared it to his Servants, and as it was
declared when the Trumpet firſt began to ſound,
ſo now all is done, and the ſolemn Oath of the Eter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal
God is to be given to you, to deſide all matters
of Controverſy, and you ſhall know whoſe Words
ſhall ſtand, His, or yours,</hi> Rev. 10. 5, 6, 7. And the
angel which I ſaw ſtand upon the ſea, and upon the
earth, lifted up his hand to heaven, And ſware by him
that liveth for ever and ever, who created heaven, and
the things that therein are; and the earth, and the
things that therein are; and the ſea, and the things
which are therein, that there ſhould be time no longer:
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:170770:8"/>
But in the days of the voice of the ſeventh angel, when
he ſhall ſound, and the miſtery of God be finiſhed, as
he hath declared unto his ſervants the prophets. <hi>The
ſeventh Angel hath ſounded, and the Myſtery of
God is finiſhed, and there is time no longer, not a
Moment, nor a Minute, for,</hi> The kingdoms of this
world are become the kingdoms of our Lord, and of
his Christ, and he ſhall reign for ever and ever, <hi>Rev.</hi>
11. 15. Blow ye the trumpet in Zion, and ſound an
alarm in my holy mountain: let all the inhabitants of
the earth tremble: for the day of the Lord cometh,
it is nigh at hand, <hi>Joel</hi> 2. 1. A voice from the city, a
voice from the temple, a voice of the Lord that ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreth
recompenſe to his enemies, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 66. 6.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:170770:8"/>
And he ſaith unto me, Seal not the ſayings of the
Propheſie of this Book, for the time is at hand.</p>
            <p>He that is unjuſt, let him be unjuſt ſtill: and he
which is filthy, let him be filthy ſtill: and he that
is righteous, let him be righteous ſtill: and he
that is holy, let him be holy ſtill.</p>
            <p>And behold, I come quickly, and my reward is with
me, to give to every Man according as his work
ſhall be, <hi>Revel. 12. chap.</hi> 10, 11, 12.</p>
            <p>YOU are to take notice, That the <hi>Rage</hi> and <hi>Tu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mult</hi>
that hath been in this Nation, hath been
againſt the Revelation of <hi>Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> which God
gave him, to ſhew to his Servants; and this Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed
Servant of God, (that hath been trampled, as
the Mire in the Streets, is that Angel ſpoke of in
the <hi>Revelations,</hi> that was ſent to ſhew Gods Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants
the things that muſt be done in a ſhort time;
therefore, there is no anſwer can be given to God
for theſe things, when his Word had expreſsly ſpoke
of a Meſſenger that was to come; and the day
came, and the Meſſenger was ſent; and this was
Witneſſed to them by a certain number of Souls
that God appointed to be Witneſſes, that God had
ſhewed the things that muſt be done in a ſhort
time, but they wilfully ſhut their Eyes: God hath
worked a work, and a marvellous work, but they
would not Believe, though it was told them.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:170770:9"/>
I further bear Witneſs, that the Woman in the
Wilderneſs, hath brought forth a Man Child, that
ſhall rule all Nations with a Rod of Iron; and tho'
the Dragon hath raged &amp; blaſphemed, and this day
thrown a third part of the Stars to the Earth; yet
all is in Vain, for the Child is caught up to God,
and to his Throne, <hi>Revel. 12. And our God hath ſet
up a kingdom which ſhall never be deſtroyed; but it
ſhall break and deſtroy all kingdoms, and it ſhall
ſtand for ever and ever.</hi> And all theſe things that
have been here done in Spirit and in Miſtery, ſhall
quickly be made viſible and ſenſible things in the
ſight of all the World.</p>
            <p>THE Revelation of Jeſus Christ, which God
gave unto him, to ſhew unto his ſervants the
things which muſt ſhortly come to paſs; and he ſent
and ſignified it by his angel unto his ſervant John:
Who bare record of the word of God, and of the teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony
of Jeſus Christ, and of all things that he ſaw,
<hi>Rev. 1. 1, 2. I bear witneſs, That in the Year 1689,
there came a Meſſenger from God, and declared,</hi>
That the Lord would have a Kingdom in this World,
and the time draws near, behold I come quickly, and
ſurely I come quickly, <hi>Rev.</hi> 22. God will deliver
the creation from the bondage of corruption, into the
glorious liberty of the ſons of God, <hi>Rom.</hi> 8. And
there ſhall be no more ſorrow, nor death, nor pain, he
will ſit upon the throne, and make all new; the taber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nacle
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:170770:9"/>
of God ſhall be with men; there ſhall be a new
heaven, and a new earth, and Babylon ſhall be thrown
down; the Jews called; and the ends of the earth
brought in; and the Dragon chained.</p>
            <p>God commands the Trumpet to be ſounded, <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pent
quickly, or you will be in hell quickly.</hi> When
the ſhewing time and fufilling Miſtery was ended,
one of <hi>Philadelphia</hi> received this Word from God,
<hi>He hath ſent his angel to ſhew the things that muſt be
done in a ſhort time:</hi> Now they are to be done.
The Lord's Servant alſo himſelf declared, <hi>That the
hand of God had been ſtrong upon him, to write, the
words that I have ſpoken ſhall be done, ſaith the Lord.</hi>
And now a new courſe was ſpeedily entered upon,
<hi>The heavens are planted, and the foundations of the
earth laid, and now God ſaith unto Zion, thou art my
people,</hi> Iſa. 5. 6. In which time, we <hi>ſaw the new
heaven, and the new earth, and heard that mighty
voice, The tabernacle of God is with man: And he
that ſits on the throne, and ſaith, Behold, I make all
things new; And there is a rainbow round about the
throne,</hi> Rev. 4. 3. At this time, that <hi>Bleſſed Oath</hi>
that hath ſtood ſo many 100 Years in <hi>Rev.</hi> 10. 6.
is ſworn in the heart of a poor Worm, to be a Sign
and a Witneſs to the Church of <hi>Philadelphia,</hi> that
God remembers the <hi>Oath</hi> which he ſware to <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi>
that ancient <hi>Oath</hi> and <hi>Covenant</hi> which we ſo
often read of in the Word of God; <hi>And this ſhall
be as the waters of</hi> Noah <hi>unto me: the mountains
ſhall depart, and the hills be removed; but the cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:170770:10"/>
of his peace ſhall never be removed,</hi> Iſa. 54. 9, 10.
And now the Rainbow appear'd, Temptations,
Sins, and Sorrows, were all on a ſudden removed
and took away, and I wrapt up into thoſe Kingdom
Joys, that I ſcarce knew what they were doing
here on Earth: But I can bear witneſs, <hi>That I ſaw
the heavens planted, and the foundations of the earth
laid, and that God ſaid to Zion, thou art my people,</hi>
Iſa. 51. 16. At this time the Voices were heard,
the Viſions ſeen ſet down in the Book of the <hi>Reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lations,</hi>
and Witneſs born to the keeping of theſe
Sayings of the Prophecy of that Book. The time
that was taken up in the fulfilling of theſe things
continued near 2 Years, to my beſt Remembrance;
but before all was finiſhed, a ſign of Deliverance
was given to the Church of <hi>Philadelphia:</hi> theſe
Words being ſent to the Lord's Servant, that he
having looked upon the Sorrows of his poor loſt
<hi>Zion, Lifts up his hand to heaven, and ſwares by him
that liveth for ever and ever, that there ſhould be
time no longer:</hi> And, <hi>Here now, O Joſhua the high
priest, thou and thy fellows, ye are men wondred at:
but behold, I bring forth my ſervant the BRANCH,</hi>
Zech. 3. 8. Eſtabliſhed for ever is his Word in
Heaven; ſignified, ſealed, and ratified upon Earth;
but we knew not what theſe things meant, until
the Lord's Servant came with theſe Words from
God; <hi>Behold the Man, whoſe name is the BRANCH.</hi>
See the Chriſt of God given to you out of the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther's
own hand; here's the viſible, ſenſible, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vailed
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:170770:10"/>
Chriſt performed to you: <hi>And the ſeventh
angel poured out his vial into the air; and a great
voice came out of the temple of heaven from the throne,
ſaying, It is done,</hi> Rev. 16. 17. Enter <hi>Philadelphia,</hi>
in the Name of the Father, and of the Son, and of
the Holy-Ghoſt; the Lord he declares the Reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation
(which is a Prophecy of a Prophecy) is
fulfilled; <hi>The voices have been heard, and the viſions
ſeen, and the words of the prophecy of the book have
been kept from that word,</hi> Rev. 1. 3. <hi>Bleſſed is he
that reads, and they that hear,</hi> until that Sentence
was pronounced upon them, <hi>They ſhall reign for
evermore,</hi> Rev. 22. <hi>And then the mighty angel came
down with a rainbow on his head; and the little book
open in his hand, and lift up his hand to heaven, and
ſware by him who lives for ever and ever, who created
the heaven, and the things that therein are; and the
earth, and the things that therein are; and the Sea,
and the things that therein are; that there ſhould
be time no longer.</hi> O joyful happy day. And the
Lord himſelf deſcended from Heaven with a Shout,
and with the Voice of the Arch-Angel, and the
Ark of his Teſtament was ſeen in his Temple, and
they were called to return thanks to God, and
to ſing with gladneſs for <hi>Jacob;</hi> and the Lord ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peared
to his Servant, as a <hi>Zion</hi>'s God, and then re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived
him to himſelf, on whom he had writ the
Name of the City of his God; <hi>for the new Jeruſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lem
comes down out of heaven from God,</hi> Rev. 21. 2,
10, 11. I witneſs, That this <hi>Oath</hi> continued with
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:170770:11"/>
that ſtrength and power upon me, that (like Fire)
it broke through all that was caſt upon me, to
damp it, till the ſame Words were put into his Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants
Mouth, according to that Scripture, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 59.
21. and then the Everlaſting Covenant being pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nounced,
with the <hi>Oath</hi> of the Eternal God, it was
declared, in the Name of God, That the Lyon of
the Tribe of <hi>Judah</hi> had prevailed, and they that
had kept the Words of the Prophecy of this Book,
are all Conquerours in Him; and as we had derived
all Guilt and Miſery, Death and Sorrow, in the
firſt <hi>Adam;</hi> ſo now we are come to inherit all Grace,
Glory, and Comfort, which came by the New; we
are come to the Blood of ſprinkling, &amp; to the Spirits
of juſt Men made perfect, <hi>Heb.</hi> 12. And that God
that had ſet the bounds to the old <hi>Adam,</hi> hath took
an <hi>Oath</hi> of the time, and he is curſed and gone for
ever; <hi>The Seed of the woman hath broke the ſerpent's
head. I heard a loud voice ſaying in heaven, Now is
come ſalvation, and ſtrength, and the kingdom of our
God, and the power of his Chriſt,</hi> Rev. 12. 10. After
theſe things the Lord ſhewed us, as there had been
a dark and obſcure Sign in the Church of <hi>Phila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delphia,</hi>
a <hi>Rainbow,</hi> and a pouring down of the
Spirit, for a Covenant for <hi>Zion,</hi> Iſa. 59. 21. ſo now
there ſhould be a bright and glorious <hi>Sign, Iſa.</hi> 66.
18, 19. And he will bring all Nations, and they
ſhall ſee his Glory, for he will ſet up a<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Sign amongſt
them; and in this Mountain will the Lord take
away the Vail that is ſpread over all Nations, for
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:170770:11"/>
he will ſwallow up Death in Victory, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 25. 7, 8.
After theſe things God ordered it to be declared,
That the days of the voice of the ſeventh Angel
was ended, he had finiſhed his courſe, and kept
the Faith, and received the Crown of Righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs,
which the Lord, the Righteous Judge, had
given him; and that the Church of <hi>Philadelphia</hi>
is that Stone ſpoke of, <hi>Zech.</hi> 3. 9. And that Stone
ſhall bear witneſs, for it hath heard all the words
of the Prophecy of that Book: And, in the Name
of God it was declared, That the Law of God was
writ upon that Stone, according to theſe Words,
<hi>Jer. 31. 33. The day is come, ſaith the Lord<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> that I
will make a new covenant with the houſe of Iſrael, and
with the houſe of Judah, and I will put my law in
their inward parts, and write it in their hearts.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Object I.</hi> This means Zion.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſwer.</hi> This is <hi>Zion</hi>'s Repreſentative, this is
that elect Seed that was to inherit God's Holy
Mountain, as you may ſee, <hi>Iſa. 65. 9. Rev.</hi> 3. 12.
I will write upon them the name of the City of my God.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Object II.</hi> Where is this New Covenant?</p>
            <p>Anſwer. I ſaw a mighty angel come down from hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven
with a rainbow upon his head; and the angel which
I ſaw ſtand upon the ſea, and upon the earth, lift up
his hand to heaven, and ſware by him that liveth for
ever and ever, that time ſhould be no longer. <hi>I bear
witneſs, in the preſence of God, this</hi> Oath<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
               <hi>hath been
ſworn and performed to the Church of</hi> Philadel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phia,
<hi>as</hi> Zion<hi>'s repreſentative,</hi> Iſa. 59. 21. As for
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:170770:12"/>
me, this is my covenant, ſaith the Lord, My ſpirit
that is upon thee, and the words that I have put into
thy mouth, ſhall not depart out of thy mouth, nor out of
the mouth of thy ſeeds ſeed, ſaith the Lord, from
henceforth and for ever. Ariſe, ſhine, for thy light
is come, and the glory of the Lord is riſen upon thee,
<hi>Iſa. 50. 1. I bear witneſs, That the Angel of the
Church of</hi> Philadelphia <hi>hath the higheſt badge of
Honour writ on him, that ever was engraven on
the Sons of Men;</hi> For he hath writ on him the name
of God, and the name of the city of his God, which is
new Jeruſalem, which comes out of heaven from God,
<hi>Rev. 3. 12. and</hi> 21. 2, 10, 11. He writ on him
his new name, <hi>King of kings, and Lord of lords;
for as he repreſented our Lord Jeſus in all his Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces
of the Kingdom, during the time they were
done in Spirit and Miſtery; ſo he ſhall do a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain,
when they are done viſibly and ſenſibly in the
Eyes of all the World; and as we have heard that
mighty Voice, ſaying,</hi> Babylon the great is fallen,
is fallen; <hi>ſo we ſhall ſee that</hi> other angel come down
from heaven, having great power, and the earth ſhall
be lightned with his glory, <hi>Rev.</hi> 18. He was that olive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tree
that ſtood on the right-ſide of the bowl, that was on
the top of the golden candleſtick. He was that anointed
one that ſtood before the God of the whole earth, <hi>Zech.</hi>
4. 14. He is that prophet that had power to ſmite
the earth with all manner of plagues, as oft as he
would, <hi>Rev.</hi> 11. 6. For the land is utterly emptied,
and ſpoiled: the Lord hath ſpoken this word, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 24. 3.
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:170770:12"/>
               <hi>but the dreadful Sentences of his Judgments are
now to be executed on a ſinful God-daring Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration,
that ſcorned to take any Warning, till
Himſelf ſhould come and take Vengeance on them.
Yet bleſſed be his glorious Name; there is a</hi> Rain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bow
<hi>round about his Throne, and when he ſhall
bring a Cloud and cover the Earth, the</hi> Bow <hi>ſhall
be ſeen in the Cloud, and he will remember the</hi>
Everlaſting Covenant: <hi>Glory to the Righteous, we
have a full aſſurance of Faith, we ſhall ſee an innu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merable
Company of all Kindreds, People, Tongues
and Nations with white Robes, and Palms in their
hands, crying,</hi> Salvation to him that ſits on the throne<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
and to the lamb for ever and ever. <hi>And for all
theſe things, Bleſſing, Glory, Wiſdom, Honour, and
Might, be unto our God for ever and ever.</hi>
            </p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Laws, Statutes, and Judgments, to
the Church of Philadelphia.</head>
               <p>THAT that I am to Witneſs to you now, is
that which was declared by the Lord's Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant,
whilſt the Myſtery of God was finiſhed, and
witneſſed by the Church of <hi>Philadelphia,</hi> was the
<hi>Laws, Statutes,</hi> and <hi>Judgments</hi> of the Eternal God,
that ſtand faſt for ever and ever, throughout all
Generations. And when the Word came forth in
the Father's Seaſon; <hi>He that ſits on the throne ſaith,
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:170770:13"/>
behold, I make all things new:</hi> The Lord pointed
me to Witneſs to it, and write it down, and gave
it to his Servant; 'tis gone forth in Righteouſneſs,
and ſhall return no more, till it hath formed <hi>the
new heaven, and the earth.</hi> You will ſay, How
ſhould I know, that that Word was gone forth in
Righteouſneſs. Alas! I knew no more than a ſtock,
or a ſtone; but the Lord made me know that it
was the Word of God, and the Teſtimony of Jeſus,
and that I muſt bear witneſs to it; and I could
have no eaſe in my Conſcience till I had done it;
and again, <hi>when the heavens were planted, and the
foundations of the earth laid, and he ſaid to Zion,
thou art my people.</hi> That Lord ſent me to bear wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs;
<hi>I ſaw the new heaven, and the new earth; and
he had ſworn in my heat, time ſhould be no longer:
The day is come, he makes a new covenant with the
houſe of Iſrael,</hi> Jer. 31. 31. Theſe Myſteries were
as far above the reach of ſuch a poor Worm as I,
as the Heavens are above the Earth; for, when I
was ſo wrapt up in the ſight of <hi>the new heavens,
and the new earth,</hi> I could not forbear ſaying, as I
went up and down, <hi>I ſee a new heaven, and a new
earth;</hi> it was as wonderful to me, when I heard
thoſe Words, <hi>Rev.</hi> 21. as if I had never known
there had been any ſuch Scripture: therefore God
forbid that you ſhould think there was any thing
in the Creature in theſe things; I did alſo, about
this time, ſeveral times here Voices, and they were
thoſe Voices in <hi>Revelations;</hi> and I knew when I
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:170770:13"/>
heard it, it was the Voice of God, differing from
all other that ever I heard in all my life-time; and
when-ever I heard a Voice, or ſaw a Viſion, or
bore witneſs to any of the Words of the Prophecy
of that Book, I was ſo awed with it, that I durſt
never entertain a thought ever any more againſt it;
it became a perpetual law in my Soul; and when
the Bleſſing was pronounced upon the Church of
<hi>Philadelphia</hi> in a Miniſterial way, the Lord ſent me
to bear witneſs to it, <hi>Rev. 1. 3. Bleſſed is he that
readeth, and they that hear the word of the prophecy
of this book:</hi> and he had declared the Downfall of
<hi>Babylon,</hi> and the chaining of Satan; the Lord made
us ſee it done in an Angelical way, and ſo bare
witneſs to it, according to theſe words, <hi>Rev.</hi> 20. 1.
<hi>I ſaw an angel come down from heaven, having the
key of the bottomleſs pit, and a great chain in his hand,
and he laid hold on the dragon, that old ſerpent, called
the devil and ſatan, and bound him for a 1000 years.</hi>
Rev. 18. <hi>I ſaw another angel come down from heaven,
and he cryed mightily with a ſtrong voice, ſaying<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
Babylon the great is fallen, is fallen:</hi> Again, when
the ſeventh Angel had poured out his Vial into the
Air, <hi>a great voice came out of the temple of heaven
from the throne, ſaying, It is done,</hi> enter <hi>Philadel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phia,</hi>
in the Name of the Father, Son, and Holy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>Ghoſt,
the Lord ſent me to bear Record to the
Word of God, and to the Teſtimony of Jeſus
Chriſt, <hi>That we are now entered into the Paradice,
where there is no more curſe; but the Throne of God,
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:170770:14"/>
and of the Lamb, are in it, and his ſervants ſhall
ſerve him; and they ſhall ſee his face, and his name
ſhall be in their foreheads; and there ſhall be no
night there, and they need no candle, neither
the light of the ſon, for the Lord God gives them
light; and they ſhall reign for ever and ever.</hi> Some
of theſe things I am forced to bear witneſs too,
that all the World may know, that the Words of
the Kingdom are no cunning deviſed Fables, when
our Bleſſed Lord and<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Saviour came and wrought
thoſe Miracles that never Man did, yet they would
not believe; but ſaid, <hi>He caſt out devils by Beel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zebub,
the prince of devils.</hi> What a dreadful Sen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence
he paſſed on them; therefore, ſaid he, <hi>All
manner of ſins and blaſphemies ſhall be forgiven; but
the blaſphemy of the Holy-Ghoſt ſhall never be for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>given.</hi>
You muſt think, God will ſtand up for
his great Honour and Name; <hi>and call all nations
together: Who amongſt them can declare this,</hi> Iſa.
43. 9. Could all the Art in Heaven and Earth
have cauſed one of theſe Voices to have been heard,
or Viſions to be ſeen, or one Word of the Prophecy
of this Book to have been kept, without the om<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nipotent
power of God. Indeed, we might have
ſeen theſe things with our bodily Eyes, when they
had been done to our outward Senſes; but to ſee
them with Chriſt's ſeven Eyes which are upon the
Stone, that can be attributed to none but God
Himſelf. Can you think (without a Commiſſion
from God) any under the Copes of Heaven durſt be
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:170770:14"/>
ſo audacious, as to take his Sacred Name into
their Mouth, and come and witneſs, and affirm,
before all the World, <hi>The keeping of the ſayings of
the prophecy of this book,</hi> when ſuch a dreadful Sen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence
is paſſed on them, <hi>That ſhall add to theſe
things,</hi> Rev. 22. 18. but ſo great and vaſt are theſe
Miſteries above the comprehenſion of Men and
Angels, no Word can utter, or Tongue expreſs;
what is here delivered, is but a ſhort account of
ſome few particular things, to be a Teſtimony to
you of the fulfilling of the whole Book; but you
muſt look to it, for what comes to you, is the
Word of God, and Teſtimony of Jeſus Chriſt.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Object.</hi> But we look for viſible ſenſible things.</p>
               <p>Anſwer. <hi>That we are bound in Conſcience, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe
of this Word,</hi> every moment to expect the
great change that comes on the whole world: <hi>but yet,
if the Word of God, and Teſtimony of Jeſus, be
not as much aſſurance to me, as theſe viſible ſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible
things, how dare we think we ſhall ſee them,
when</hi> he that takes away from the words of the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phecy
of this book, God takes his part out of the book
of life, and out of the holy city, and from the things
that are written in this book. He that teſtifieth theſe
things, ſaith, Surely I come quickly. Ariſe, and trim
your lamps, for he hath witneſſed and teſtified, All is
done. <hi>You know,</hi> at the firſt creation all was done
by his word: God ſaid, Let it be ſo, and it was ſo,
<hi>Gen. 1. Iſa. 48. 13. Heb. 11. 3. Iſa. 45. 12. Zech.</hi>
4. 6. <hi>Pſal. 33. 6, 9. The reaſon why we ſaw</hi> the
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:170770:15"/>
new heaven, and the new earth, <hi>was, That we might
bear witneſs to the Word of God, and Teſtimony
of Jeſus Chriſt; this needs not to be done when
it appears to all the World: The Scripture ſaith,</hi>
When Christ appears, we ſhall appear with him in
glory; <hi>therefore that cannot be the time when ſo
great and wonderful a Controverſie is to be deſided.
That the Eternal Majeſty of Heaven, that never
did any thing in vain, ſhould come with ſo many
Words, and ſuch a ſolemn Oath, read</hi> Revel. 10.
<hi>bear witneſs, that we do proteſt to you, by the
Eternal God,</hi> That we have ſeen that mighty angel
come down from heaven, cloathed with a cloud, and a
rainbow was upon his head, and an open book in his
hand: and he hath ſet his right foot upon the ſea,
and his left foot upon the earth, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 2. 8. And he
cries, as when a lyon roars, <hi>Mat.</hi> 25. 6. And the an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gel
which I ſaw ſtand upon the ſea, and upon the earth,
hath lift up his hand to heaven, and hath ſworn by him
that liveth for ever and ever, who created heaven,
and the things that therein are; the earth, and the
things that therein are; the ſea, and the things that
are therein; there ſhall be time no longer: for the
ſeventh angel hath ſounded, and the miſtery of God
is finiſhed: <hi>And by the God of Truth,</hi> The king<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms
of this world are become the kingdoms of our
Lord, and of his Christ; and he ſhall reign for ever
and ever. <hi>Amen. Hallalujah.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Go forth, ye daughters of Zion, and behold king
Solomon with the crown wherewith his mother crowned
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:170770:15"/>
him, in the day of his eſpouſals, and in the day of
the gladneſs of his heart, <hi>Cant.</hi> 3. 11. Behold, the
Bridegroom cometh, <hi>Mat.</hi> 25.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="song">
               <head>The New SONG.</head>
               <l>
                  <hi>O<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>R JESUS</hi> this day is proclaimed,</l>
               <l>In our Streets he is viſibly Crowned,</l>
               <l>And highly renowned.</l>
               <l>Our <hi>JESUS</hi> this Day is proclaimed,</l>
               <l>In our Streets he is viſibly Crowned,</l>
               <l>And highly renowned.</l>
               <l>From the <hi>Eaſt</hi> from the <hi>Weſt,</hi> from the <hi>North</hi> from the <hi>South,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Is the Language I hear in every Mouth,</l>
               <l>That <hi>JESUS</hi> is King, let's joyfully ſing,</l>
               <l>Our <hi>JESUS</hi> is King, our <hi>JESUS</hi> is King.</l>
               <l>That <hi>JESUS,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
               <l>All Glory, all Glory, all Glory alone,</l>
               <l>To the Glory that ſits on the glorious Throne.</l>
               <l>All Glory, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>All Heavenly ſweet Flowers be ſtrewed in his ways,</l>
               <l>Hallelujahs, Hoſannahs, and Millions of Praiſes.</l>
               <l>All Glory is due,</l>
               <l>To the Holy and True,</l>
               <l>Who ſits on the Throne, and makes all New.</l>
               <l>
                  <pb n="24" facs="tcp:170770:16"/>
Come now to his Temple, ye lookers for <hi>JESUS,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>His Honour advance, and his Praiſe in the Dance.</l>
               <l>Come now to his Temple, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Break forth into Singing, ye Mountains and Woods,</l>
               <l>For Joy clap your hands, ye Fountains and Floods.</l>
               <l>Let Him be ador'd by Angels and Men,</l>
               <l>And <hi>Zion</hi> adorn'd with her Tabrets again.</l>
               <l>Let Him, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Come away to his Courts, ye longers for <hi>JESUS,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>His Honour advance, and his Praiſe in the Dance.</l>
               <l>Come away, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Break forth into Singing, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Let Him be adored, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Come away to his Courts, ye Lovers of <hi>JESUS,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>His Honour advance, his Praiſe in the Dance.</l>
               <l>Come away, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Break forth, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Let Him be adored, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </l>
            </div>
            <div type="song">
               <pb n="25" facs="tcp:170770:16"/>
               <head>The SONG of Moſes the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant
of God, and the Lamb.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>GREAT and Marvellous are thy Works,</l>
                  <l>Jehovah working Wonders;</l>
                  <l>It lightens when our Lord appears,</l>
                  <l>And when he ſpeaks it thunders.</l>
                  <l>Moſt Juſt and True are all thy ways,</l>
                  <l>Thy Saints ſhall bleſs thee all their days;</l>
                  <l>Thou art our King, they gladly Sing,</l>
                  <l>Thy Subjects are before Thee.</l>
                  <l>Moſt Juſt and True, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Had People known thy Glorious Name<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </l>
                  <l>They would have gloried Thee:</l>
                  <l>For, Lord, thou art that Holy One,</l>
                  <l>And there is none beſides Thee.</l>
                  <l>The Nations all ſhall flock and meet<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </l>
                  <l>With bowed Faces at thy Feet,</l>
                  <l>Thy Judgments ſhew thy Glory now;</l>
                  <l>Let all the World adore Thee.</l>
                  <l>The Nations all, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="epigraph">
               <pb n="26" facs="tcp:170770:17"/>
               <head>
                  <bibl>Revelations 22. 16, 17.</bibl>
               </head>
               <p>I Jeſus have ſent mine angel, to
teſtifie unto you theſe things in
the churches. I am the root
and off-spring of David, and
the bright and morning-ſtar.</p>
               <p>And the Spirit and the Bride
ſay, Come. And let him that
heareth, ſay, Come. And let
him that is athirſt, Come. And
whoſoever will, let him take
the water of life freely.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="27" facs="tcp:170770:17"/>
               <head>The Everlaſting Covenant produced:
With the OATH of the Eternal God,
Sworn by Him that lives for ever and ever,</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <q>Time is no longer,</q>
                  <bibl>Rev. 10. 5.</bibl>
               </epigraph>
               <epigraph>
                  <q>I lift up my hand to heaven, and ſay, I live for
ever and ever,</q>
                  <bibl>Deuter. 32. 40</bibl>
               </epigraph>
               <opener>To the Church of Philadelphia.</opener>
               <p>THAT, that I am to bear witneſs to you, is
concerning the <hi>Angels Oath,</hi> which was to
have a double fulfilment. Firſt, <hi>For a Sign then
to all the Church of</hi> Philadelphia; ſeveral courſes
was gone upon in this Bleſſed Miniſtery. Laſt of
all, <hi>The Glorious Miſtery of God was to be finiſhed.</hi>
This begun when our Lord was proclaimed
KING; and it was declared, <hi>Zion's-God now
reigns: He is upon his great white throne; and there
was a rainbow round about the throne:</hi> This was
the time that this <hi>Oath</hi> came upon me, to be a
Sign to the Church of <hi>Philadelphia,</hi> that God
remembers the<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                  <hi>Everlaſting Covenant,</hi> the <hi>Oath</hi> he
ſwore to <hi>Abraham</hi> that <hi>Oath</hi> &amp; <hi>Covenant</hi> we ſo often
read of in the Word of God; <hi>At the end of time,
times, and half a time,</hi> as it is in the laſt of <hi>Daniel.</hi>
This <hi>Oath</hi> came forth to All the Church of <hi>Phila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delphia,
Time ſhall be no longer. The Lord brought
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:170770:18"/>
forth his Servant the BRANCH.</hi> Old <hi>Adam</hi>'s
ſtate is finiſhed. After this, <hi>The Tree of Life,</hi>
which is in the midſt of the Paradice of God<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> was
given to the Church of <hi>Philadelphia,</hi> upon the
Word and Honour of the Eternal God. Now,
the certainty of our Lord's being at this time on
his Throne, making every thing New, and more
particularly, of our being under the New <hi>Adam;</hi>
becauſe the Righteous BRANCH was now
brought forth to the houſe of <hi>David; and he is called,
The</hi> LORD OUR RIGHTEOUSNESS,
<hi>Jer.</hi> 23. 6.</p>
               <p>And the Church of <hi>Philadelphia</hi> firſt pertakes
of the Grace and Glory which comes by the <hi>New
Adam; For he hath writ on them the name of the
city of his God;</hi> from theſe things I was as much aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſured,
that it was my duty to believe it was as
God ſaid, (and to take this Righteous BRANCH
which was now brought forth amongſt us, to make
us all <hi>New,</hi> Soul and Body) as I was bound to
keep any of the Commands of God. And again,
this was confirmed to us, when the Lord's Servant
came with theſe Words, <hi>Behold the man, whoſe
name is the<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> BRANCH. The Father's Day is
come, which was hid from Men and Angels. I
found theſe things ſo ſtrong and weighty, that I
could not dally with them; for, if I would have
ſaid, I did not believe, he had brought his firſt
begotten again into the World, becauſe I did not
ſee him with my bodily Eyes, my own Conſcience
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:170770:18"/>
would have condemned me, for the <hi>Oath</hi> of God
was writ in my Heart, which he had ſworn to
<hi>Philadelphia, Time ſhall be no longer: and behold
the man, whoſe name is the</hi> BRANCH.</p>
               <p>I knew in my Soul that this was the Word of
God, that the <hi>Old Adam</hi>'s State was finiſhed, which
could be done only by the coming of the <hi>New.</hi> I
muſt own it, in the preſence of God, that he hedged
me up to theſe things, and put me to that bleſſed
ſtreight, that I muſt cry out, in the Name of all
<hi>Philadelphia, Be ye lifted up ye everlaſting doers,
and the King of glory ſhall come in.</hi> And I Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſed
to them, That the Chriſt of God was not
only given to us <hi>out of the Father's own hand, in his
own ſeaſon,</hi> but cloſſed with and received, as he
was offered in the Word, <hi>in ſure and certain hopes,
that as we have born the image of the earthly, ſo now
for ever bear we the image of the heavenly Adam.</hi>
I Witneſs, that God writ it with an Iron Pen, and
the point of a Diamond on my Heart. That I
was finally, eternally, and everlaſtingly acquitted
and abſolved from all the guilt of Sin and Sorrow
which came by the firſt <hi>Adam,</hi> having received
and cloſed with the Righteous BRANCH, as he
was given out of the Father's own hand; for which
infinite Grace and Mercy, I proſtrate my ſelf in
Duſt and Aſhes at his Feet, acknowledging his
Love and Mercy to be abſolute, grounded wholly
and eternally on the Merits of his Dear Son, and
that there is nothing in any Creature. I further
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:170770:19"/>
Witneſs, That he enabled me to rely on the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fallibility
of his <hi>Word, Oath,</hi> and <hi>Teſtimony,</hi> which
from that time ſtood in full force, for the utter
deſtruction of my Sins and Corruptions. I Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs,
That I came a miſerable, diſtreſſed, tormented
Wretch, out of the <hi>Old Adam</hi>'s State, ſo that I had
longed many years for a Grave, not for any out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward
Miſeries, but conſtant wearyings and tirings
out with a Body of Sin and Death; <hi>And the man,
whoſe name is the</hi> BRANCH, <hi>that was given out
of the Father's own hand,</hi> became almoſt glorious
triumphant Conquerour over the <hi>Old Adam;</hi> and
for theſe things I bow my Knees to the Almighty,
and ſhall ſing Praiſe unto my <hi>Zion</hi>'s KING, now
and ever. <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>I Witneſs, <hi>That I heard a great voice from the
temple of heaven, from the throne, ſaying, It is done:
And then he came and writ on me his new name, King
of kings, and Lord of lords;</hi> and upon this called
me to take of the water of Life freely: <hi>And he
ſhewed me a pure river of water of life, clear as
chriſtal, proceeding out of the throne of God, and of
the Lamb,</hi> Rev. 22. 1. I Witneſs, I had not only
an outward Call in the Word, to take theſe <hi>waters
of life,</hi> but inward Illumination of his Spirit, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording
to theſe words, <hi>Rev. 22. 17. The ſpirit,
ſays, Come.</hi> All Glory to my <hi>Zion</hi>'s JESUS, now
and ever. And I took of the water of life, and ſhall
never thirſt more, it is in my Belly a well-ſpring to
Eternal Life. All Glory to the Lord alone now and
ever.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="31" facs="tcp:170770:19"/>
                  <hi>I Witneſs, That at the ſame time, he ſaid unto
me,</hi> Behold the man whoſe name is the <hi>BRANCH.</hi>
See the tree of life placed in the midſt: put forth thy
hand, fear not, take, eat, and live for ever: <hi>and he
gave me of the</hi> Tree, <hi>with theſe words,</hi> John 6. 58.
Not as your fathers eat manna, and are dead: he
that eateth of this bread, ſhall live for ever. <hi>And
for all theſe things, Bleſſing, and Honour, and Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,
and Strength, and Power, be to our God
now and ever.</hi> Amen.</p>
               <p>And there is no more curſe: but the throne of God,
and the. Lamb ſhall be in it; his ſervants ſhall ſerve
him. And ſee his face, and his name ſhall be in their
foreheads. And there ſhall be no night there, they
need no candle, nor light of the ſun; for the Lord
God giveth them light, and they ſhall reign for ever,
<hi>Rev.</hi> 22. 3, 4, 5.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>All Glory to the Lord alone, now and for ever.
After theſe things, the Lord's ſervant comes and
tells you, God hath performed his</hi> Oath, There is
time no longer. And the mighty angel comes down,
cloathed with a cloud, and a rainbow on his head, his
face ſhin'd as the ſun, and his feet as pillars of fire.
And he had in his hand a little book open: and he
ſet his right foot on the ſea, and his left foot on the
earth, And cried, as when a lyon roareth: And he
lift up his hand to heaven, and ſware by him that
liveth for ever and ever, who created heaven, and
the things that therein are; the earth, and the
things that therein are; and the ſea, and the things
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:170770:20"/>
that therein are; that there ſhould be time no
longer, <hi>Rev.</hi> 10. 1, 2, 3, 6.</p>
               <p>I Witneſs, That on this ſame day, I had a ſtrict
<hi>Commiſſion</hi> from <hi>God,</hi> to tell you, with other things,
<hi>That a ſign of deliverance to the Church of</hi> Philadel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phia,
ſignified, God's <hi>Oath</hi> to them. The Lord
tells you, <hi>He hath performed his Oath, and there is
time no longer;</hi> the <hi>Old Adam</hi>'s ſtate is finiſhed:
And I do affirm, in the Name of the Eternal God,
That this is the Witneſs of Him that is Faithful
and True; and that he doth, hath, and ſhall for
ever ſway his Kingly Scepter in my Soul, and he
hath conquered the <hi>Old Adam.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And, once more, in the Name of the Lord, I
do affirm, for the Honour of his <hi>Word</hi> and <hi>Oath,</hi>
That<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> he did come down, on this ſame day, with
a rainbow on his head, as a moſt glorious trium<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phant
Conquerour over the <hi>Old Adam;</hi> and that
<hi>he did remove the iniquity of the land in one day,</hi>
Zech. 3. 9. <hi>And the mountains ſhall depart, and
the hills be removed; but the covenant of his peace
ſhall never be removed,</hi> Iſa. 54. 10.</p>
               <p>I bear witneſs, That poor <hi>Zion</hi> which had lain
ſo many 100 Years under the Guilt of that Blood
which they ſhed; and they have this day a foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain
opened for ſin and uncleanneſs<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                  <hi>Zech.</hi> 13. 1.
he hath opened the peoples graves, and the dead
bodies live again, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 37. 12. I Witneſs, That
the Redeemer is come to <hi>Zion,</hi> and hath turned
away ungodlineſs from <hi>Jacob, Iſa.</hi> 5<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 9. 20. Oh!
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:170770:20"/>
with what Adorations of Soul ſhould we worſhip
that God, that hath remembred his <hi>Covenant</hi> to a
Thouſand Generations; his Oath to <hi>Abraham,</hi>
and his Seed for ever. And the whole Creation
ſhall now break forth into the high Praiſes of
God, becauſe the Adoption is come, and it is <hi>deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered
from the bondage of Sin and Corruption, into
the glorious liberty of the Sons of God,</hi> Rom. 8. 21.
But oh! how much more ſhould <hi>Philadelphia</hi> be
night and day at this Work, who hath been ſo
highly favoured of God, to ſee theſe things with
the ſeven Eyes that are upon the Stone, before
there was any viſible appearance in the World;
thou elect Seed that was to Inherit God's Holy
Mountain, on whom he hath writ the Names of
the City of his God, the People that was to be
born to praiſe him; come and adore before his
Feet, for thou ſhalt again be <hi>Adorned with Tabrets,
and ſhall go forth in the Dance,</hi> Jer. 31. 4. for
that God that hath finiſhed the dark obſcure Sign,
appears in the bright and glorious Sign: You
will ſay, Was not the Sign finiſhed before?
<hi>Anſw.</hi> It is more than two Years ſince the My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery
of God began to be fulfilled; and the Lord
appoints Witneſs from time to time to be given
in, that ſuch and ſuch things was fulfilled and
done: And we thought every Word to be the
Laſt, and that no more was to be done for this
bleſſed Olive Tree, that had ſo long emptied the
Oyl through the Pipe into the Candleſtick. God
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:170770:21"/>
ſhews him that he was to be removed and ſtand
in another place; and ſo he tells you he had but
a very little more to ſay to you; and after this de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clares,
That the days of the voice of the ſeventh An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gel
are ended, and the Lord receives him to himſelf.
And then the dark hour comes on <hi>Philadelphia,
Thy Sons have fainted, they lye as a wild Bull in
a Net, full of the fury of the Lord,</hi> Iſai. 51. 20.
The Beaſt that aſcended out of the bottomleſs Pit
is now permitted to make War, Overcome and
Kill; alas, what was we able to do! now it was
God's infinite Mercy, and he alone that enabled
us to hold what we had received. My dear
Friends, I drunk with you of this bitter Cup;
but it was moſt grief to me at the beginning of
the Sickneſs of the Lord's Servant, and it con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued
until God had ended his Sorrow: And then
I was again received into thoſe Joys and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forts
that I was in before, and ordered to go on
Witneſſing to things as I had long before. And
many Ingravenings after this time came upon my
Soul, from which I was forced to conclude, that
the Myſtery of God on both parts was not fully
ended before; for as it was all along, firſt we re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived
the Word, then God writ-his Law upon
it. It was Sworn, <hi>Time is no longer;</hi> and this is the
Witneſs to that <hi>Oath,</hi> and the Ingravenings of God
that is come upon it. I witneſs, That <hi>Zerub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>babel,</hi>
that laid the Foundation of this Houſe, his
hands have finiſhed it, <hi>Zech.</hi> 4. 9. and the Lord
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:170770:21"/>
of Hoſts hath ſent him unto us, and now ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting
Crowns of Honour and Glory for ever
ſhine upon his Royal Princely Head, that hath
laid the top Stone in Glory; Grace, Grace, Come
away <hi>Philadelphia,</hi> down down upon your Face
before him that ſits upon the Throne, Worſhip
the Lamb, that only was found Worthy to open
the Book to read and look thereon; and every
Creature in Heaven and Earth, and under the
Earth, and ſuch ar are in the Sea, heard I, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,
<hi>Bleſſing, and Honour, and Glory, and Power be
unto him that ſitteth on the Throne, and unto the
Lamb for ever and ever,</hi> Rev. 5. 13. And ſo God
Almighty bleſs you, and turn you into a Rain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bow,
for a Sign and Covenant unto <hi>Zion,</hi> and
all the Churches; and make thee a burning and
ſhining Candleſtick before the Throne of his
Glory; to whom be Glory and Dominion now
and ever. <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="testimony">
               <pb n="36" facs="tcp:170770:22"/>
               <head>To the Church of Philadelphia.</head>
               <p>I Bear witneſs this day, That Chriſt is the True
and Faithful Witneſs; one Word hath not
failed of all the good things that he hath pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſed.
<hi>I have overcome only by the blood of the
Lamb, and no other way have I entered the gates
into the city, but by the tree of life.</hi> I hate and
deteſt all mine own righteouſneſs, I loath it as
filthy raggs, and menſtrous cloaths. I Witneſs
to you, as one of <hi>Zion</hi>'s Repreſentatives, That I
have received the fine Linnen, clean and white,
to be dreſt up for the everlaſting Bridegroom of
my Soul. The day, the day, the glorious day is
come, <hi>That he hath raiſed up to David a righteous</hi>
BRANCH; and this is the Name whereby
he is called, <hi>The</hi> LORD OUR RIGHTE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>OUSNESS.
Holy, Holy, Glory, Glory; now
muſt we contribute to that Everlaſting Hallelu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jah,
which ſhall be ſung to free Grace and Mercy
to all Eternity.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>I Witneſs, That our honoured Friend was the
true Meſſenger and Fore-runner of the Coming
and Kingdom of our Lord and Saviour Jeſus
Chriſt; and what God hath promiſed to the An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gel
of the Church of</hi> Philadelphia, <hi>is this day
performed;</hi> for he hath ſet before him that open
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:170770:22"/>
door, which none can ever ſhut. <hi>I alſo Witneſs, That
there is ſuch a thing,</hi> as entring in through the gate
into the city. <hi>Rev.</hi> 22. 14. At the gates are twelve
angels, <hi>Rev.</hi> 21. 12. The walls of the city have
twelve foundations. <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pon her head was a crown of
twelve ſtars, <hi>Rev. 12. 1. I Witneſs,</hi> That Christ
is the door, and none can enter in but by the tree of
life. He that takes away from the words of the
book of this prophecy, <hi>is condemned already,</hi> his part
is took out of the holy city, and of the book of life,
<hi>Rev.</hi> 22. 19.</p>
               <p>And now for ever bleſs I God for the Doctrine
of the Kingdom. O God, thy Teſtimony, and
the Laws of thy Mouth, have been more to me
than thouſands of Gold and Silver. My Dear
<hi>Philadelphia,</hi> Love the Word of God, and Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony
of Jeſus Chriſt; by which abundant en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trance
is miniſtered to us into the Everlaſting
Kingdom of our Lord and Saviour Jeſus Chriſt.
Glory, Glory.</p>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            </div>
            <div type="testimony">
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:170770:23"/>
               <head>Another Witneſs.</head>
               <p>I Do Teſtify, in the Name of Jeſus Chriſt, <hi>King
of kings, and Lord of lords,</hi> That the Lord
hath remembred his Servant <hi>Jacob,</hi> and hath de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared
and ſaved, and hath given to them the
Land of <hi>Canaan,</hi> according to his Word, that he
would ſettle them after their old eſtate, and do
better for them than at the beginning, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 36.
11. and that the Adoption is come, and the Glory
is come, and the Devil is bound, and the <hi>Old Adams</hi>
State is finiſhed, and all is done, <hi>Rev. 16. 17. And
time is no longer:</hi> and <hi>the Lord himſelf deſcended
from heaven with the voice of the arch-angel;</hi> and
I was Eye-Witneſs of his Majeſty; and for this,
Bleſſing, Glory, and Thankſgiving, be unto our
God, and <hi>Zion</hi>'s God; and our King, and <hi>Zion</hi>'s
King, now and ever, now and ever; Glory, Glory,
Glory to the Holy and True, that ſate on his
Throne, and made us all New. I do alſo Teſtifie,
That then we had a Perſonal Chriſt amongſt us,
and then <hi>Philadelphia</hi> was called to Sing, and
Dance, and Rejoyce, becauſe great was the Holy
One of <hi>Iſrael</hi> in the midſt of us. I alſo do Teſtifie,
That this Bleſſed Servant, that had <hi>The revelation
of Jeſus Christ, which God gave to him, to ſhew to
his ſervants things which muſt ſhortly come to
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:170770:23"/>
paſs,</hi> Rev. 1. 1. He hath ſeen the Bleſſed Perſon of
Chriſt in his Perſonal Glory; and this the Lord
hath made as plain to me, as any of the great Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſteries,
bleſſed be his Holy Name for ever and ever.
God ſhall have all the Glory for ever, and Chriſt
ſhall have all the Glory for ever, for there is no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing
in any Creature; for, <hi>All Nations are be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
him as nothing, and leſs than nothing and vanity.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>I will tell you how the Lord was pleaſed to
make it plain to me: which was,</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Firſt,</hi> He appeared in the Garment the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture
ſaid he ſhould.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Secondly,</hi> Becauſe he graciouſly promiſed, that
his Servants ſhould truſt, and not be afraid, Iſa.
12. 2. and again, he would appear the ſecond
time without Sin, to our Salvation.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Thirdly,</hi> There was ſo much Majeſty ſeen in
his Face, and yet ſo much Mercy, that his Servant,
according to his word, was enabled to truſt, and
not be afraid.</p>
               <p>I do alſo Teſtifie, in the Name of Jeſus Chriſt,
<hi>King of kings, and Lord of lords,</hi> That Mr. <hi>Maſon</hi>
was that faithful and wiſe Steward that is ſpoken
of in <hi>Luk. 12. 42, 43, 44. And the Lord made him
ruler over his houſhold, to give them their portion of
meat in due ſeaſon;</hi> and that this People that have
received the Revelation of Jeſus Chriſt, is the
houſhold there ſpoken of; <hi>and he did give us the
portion of meat in due ſeaſon;</hi> and that the Lord
hath bleſſed him of a truth, <hi>and made him ruler
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:170770:24"/>
over all that he hath.</hi> I do Teſtifie, That the Lord
hath made him chief Officer in his Kingdom.
All Glory to the Lord alone, now and ever.
Thine is the Kingdom, Power, and Glory, now
and ever, now and ever. <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Elizabeth Glover.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <epigraph>
               <q>Behold, he cometh with clouds, and
every eye ſhall ſee him, and they alſo
which pierced him; and all kindreds of
the earth ſhall wail becauſe of him: even
ſo, <hi>Amen,</hi>
               </q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Rev.</hi> 1. 7.</bibl>
            </epigraph>
            <pb facs="tcp:170770:24"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
